Andrea Diegaardt

Gauteng, South Africa



atdiegaardt@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/andy-diegaardt

Summary

I am currently a student at Microverse, a remote software development school. My passion is software development and I have been improving my skills every day through the projects we work on.

The projects I have worked on so far, using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for the first time include a portfolio project and a website where you can add books to a list and remove them from a list. I love coding, it is just so rewarding to create something from a blank page.

In the second section of this course, we moved to React/Redux, Ruby, and Ruby on Rails. After working with all of these programming languages I have discovered that while I enjoy both back-end and front-end I prefer working with front-end because I have a passion for design. I do however plan on mastering both stacks to become a great Full-Stack Developer one day.

Before changing my focus to software development I worked in customer experience. This field is very different from software development. Still, I learned many skills that I am able to use every day as a developer, including multi-tasking, planning, organization skills, and many more. I regularly received praise for my performance and attitude toward my job. I use the same motivation and energy in my growth as a software developer.

What makes me stand out is my ability to understand and work with different personalities. Not everyone has the same response or thoughts to ideas and requirements so it's important to get to know whom you are working with on a personal level. This makes the process of working together much easier and eliminates much frustration of not understanding why people do not work well together and makes it easier to resolve conflicts in an orderly manner.

Interested in chatting with me about an opportunity? Please email me atdiegaardt@gmail.com.

Experience



M High-lighted personal projects

Microverse

Jul 2022 - Present (11 months)

- Spent 1300+ hours learning full-stack development, practicing algorithms, and data structures while developing projects with JavaScript, React & Redux, Ruby, and Ruby on Rails.
- · Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, and daily standup meetings which made it easy to collaborate with international colleagues.



Junior Web Developer

3J Medical

Sep 2021 - Apr 2022 (8 months)

• Developed skills in maintaining an active website.

- · Successfully trained users on the updated website features and functionality, resulting in increased user adoption and satisfaction.
- Consistently ensured the smooth operation and reliability of software products by proactively maintaining and troubleshooting existing versions, resulting in minimal downtime and high levels of user satisfaction.



Operations, Accounts and Sales Manager

3J Medical

Aug 2021 - Apr 2022 (9 months)

- Effectively led and motivated a team of sales reps by implementing innovative strategies, resulting in a significant increase in sales within just one month.
- Fostered a supportive and collaborative team environment by investing time in understanding the individual strengths of sales reps, leading to increased morale, open communication, and improved overall performance.
- · Proactively promoted a positive team culture by organizing monthly informal gatherings, providing an opportunity for staff to socialize and connect with each other on a personal level, leading to increased team cohesion, higher job satisfaction, and improved overall performance.

Operations:

Successfully led and managed daily operations by implementing best practices in recruitment, training, and supervision, developing and executing process improvements, analyzing budgets to optimize profits, fostering a culture of motivation and positive encouragement, and proactively identifying and resolving potential issues, resulting in increased efficiency, enhanced customer service, and a highly engaged and productive team.

· Accounts:

Demonstrated a high level of competence in managing financial accounts by utilizing cutting-edge database software, proactively handling account inquiries, maintaining regular contact with clients, processing refunds, and ensuring timely payments, resulting in streamlined account management, timely payments, and enhanced client satisfaction. Successfully prepared financial reports for regulatory authorities, collected overdue payments, and established effective communication channels with clients, leading to increased efficiency, improved financial performance, and stronger client relationships.

Education



Microverse

Information Technology

Jul 2022 - Apr 2023

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.



The Gisa

MCSD, Computer Programming 2019 - 2019

The Gisa OCA, Computer Programming 2018 - 2018

Faculty of Training Institute
Certificate, Business Analysis
2012 - Present

University of Johannesburg
Certificate, Project Management
2011 - Present

Licenses & Certifications

- Microverse JavaScript Module Microverse 61081548
- Microverse Ruby/Databases Module Microverse 68346543
- Microverse HTML/CSS module Microverse 58587083
- Intro to Remote Web Development Microverse 56387906
- Microverse React & Redux Module Microverse 64241950
- Microverse Ruby on Rails Module Microverse 71096327
- Microverse Final Capstone Module Microverse 72351826

Skills

Testing • REST APIs • Sales Management • Accounts Payable (AP) • Business Strategy • Team Leadership • Team Building • Content Management Systems (CMS) • Ruby • Ruby on Rails